David Israel Ruiz Cabrera

FRONTEND DEVELOPER

I'm a Front-End Developer with more than four years of experience using HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, Sass, Material-UI JavaScript, React and Typescript, Next.js, Git/Github, Firebase, Dart and Flutter. My goal is to work remotely, collaborating with international teams and contributing to impactful projects.

PERSONAL INFORMATION

Location: Loja - Ecuador Postal code: 110102

Phone number: +593 998487957 E-mail: davidruizdeveloper@gmail.com

ACADEMIC TRAINING

2008 - 2009 Industrial Automation Specialist

Buenos Aires University

2001 - 2008 Electronics and Telecommunications Engineer

Universidad Técnica Particular de Loja

EXPERIENCE

April 2020 - Current

Content creator | Personal YouTube Channel

 I teach about various front-end technologies like HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Tailwind CSS, and React through engaging project-based tutorials.

https://www.youtube.com/CodingTube

September 2023 - December 2024

Frontend Developer | Narranz

- Developed the main application interface enabling seamless interaction with data from over 100 sensors.
- Designed and implemented new features for managing and visualizing sensor data.
- Streamlined the frontend development process by

introducing reusable component patterns.

November 2022 - December 2023

Javascript Frontend Coach | Laboratoria

- Conducted over 150 personalized one-on-one tutoring sessions, empowering students to master technical concepts in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and React, which contributed to a 95% course completion rate.
- Improved students' problem-solving abilities by guiding them through more than 100 hands-on coding challenges and real-world projects, leading to a 40% increase in their assessment scores.
- Provided emotional support and motivation, boosting student confidence and resilience, which contributed to a 20% reduction in dropout rates.
- Assisted students in creating 50+ professional-grade projects by offering guidance on best practices and industry standards, improving portfolio quality and job readiness.

April 2018 - December 2022

Project Manager | NODO CIA. LTDA.

- Led a development team of 4 members to successfully deliver 5+ software projects on time and within scope by applying Scrum methodology, achieving a 100% on-time delivery rate.
- Improved project delivery efficiency by 30% through effective sprint planning, task management, and fostering collaboration, resulting in a 20% increase in team productivity.

CERTIFICATES

December 2023	B2 English for Tech Professionals
---------------	-----------------------------------

from Unicron Academy Latam

September 2023 **B1 English for Tech Professionals**

from Unicron Academy Latam

August 2023 JavaScript Algorithms and Data Structures

from FreeCodeCamp

April 2021 JavaScript Mini-Projects - Language Learning Game

from Zenva

December 2021 Curso Práctico de Frontend Developer

from Platzi

December 2021 HTML, CSS, and Javascript for Web Developers

Jhon Hopkins University

Responsive Web Design Certification from FreeCodeCamp

LANGUAGES

English - B2 Spanish - Native